<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Dream Team]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/</link><image><url>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Dream Team</title><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 23:20:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 23:20:06 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Friend]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png">




<br><br><br>They're a monstrosity, but don't let that scare you off.<br>
Standing 8 feet tall with 4 arms, Friend is available (and eager) for a hug. Their home is a well, filled with piles of skins, brooms, equipment, and junk that Friend has collected. They also have a table set (with foods in various states of decay) for several dummies and dressing dolls, which Friend introduces as Bartholomew, Steve, Teapot, and Daisy. <br>Friend communicates telepathically to those who are willing, speaking in short, halting phrases. Their enormous insectoid figure may be intimidating, but Friend's enthusiastic waving of three arms in greeting, as well as the wailing music they play, appear to be overzealous efforts to befriend the party, apparently on the advice of Daisy. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Friend.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 23:13:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Archive 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Session 1
September 1st, 2024 (CE)<br>
Flamecrest 1, 32 (3rd Age)
<br>We begin in <a data-href="Yewdon" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Yewdon" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Yewdon</a>, where the winters are mild, and the summers are wet and damp.<br>
Going in the same direction on converging paths, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a> and <a data-href="Gerda" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda</a> meet. They discuss height differences and thought- versus leg-powered locomotion with a juxtaposition of skepticism and enthusiasm. Penelope mentioned <a data-href="Steel Jack" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Steel Jack" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Steel Jack</a>, a mentor she'd had. <br>They see a wide open plain ahead of them with two trees among the emptiness where a forest used to be.<br><img alt="twin trees.PNG" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/twin-trees.png"><br>They notice a vortex of leaves ahead around <a data-href="Elwing" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Elwing</a>. Penelope greets him, and he gives curt replies. Penelope reveals that she's here because of a dream. Elwing is too, sort of. Gerda indicates that she, too, has had a dream, but recoils at Penelope's enthusiasm. Given what they share in common, Penelope comments on the group being a "Dream Team."<br>The wind picks up, and some dark clouds start rolling in, indicating rain within the hour. They see a collection of abandoned, ruined homes off ahead, on the way toward the twin trees. Gerda starts toward the collection of shelters, signaling to the others that they could join. <br>Gerda
"Do you want to get wet?"
<br>Penelope gives Elwing the nickname "Red," when he declines to give his name.<br>
Rain begins, which Penelope has never seen before, to Gerda's astonishment.<br>
As they continue, Gerda gathers kindling. Elwing notices that the closer they get to the houses, the cooler the air has gotten.<br>There are rifts in the ground, so dark and deep that the bottom can't be seen. A strange noise emits from the manor, separate from the creaky gate swinging in the wind. It sounds like it could have been chattering voices, turning into a wailing scream, which fades into the chattering, followed by a wailing scream again.<br><img alt="friend manor exterior.jpg" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/friend-manor-exterior.jpg"><br>Red and Penelope are concerned, but Gerda is unbothered. When she sees how earnestly concerned Penelope is about the sound, however, she pauses. As they make their way around the manor and hear the wail again.<br>Elwing tells the others that he's going to find the source of the sound, but that he won't be taking care of them if they follow.<br>Inside, there are piles of skin, dead bodies in various states of decomposition, brooms, junk, equipment. It's messy, but there is intent in the organization.<br>A tall figure in the darkness of the barn emerges, swinging a tube on a string, which makes the wailing noise they had been hearing. The creature's other three arms are waving frantically.<br>Elwing speaks to the creature in Sylvan, asking who they are. It replies in an insectoid clicking sound, saying telepathically "Friend, Friend."<br>Friend
"Hello, hello. Do you like music?"
<br>Its three arms continue waving hard, expressing a fervent greeting, as it swings the screaming device. <br>Gerda draws her chef's knife to the ready. Penelope puts their welding mask down. <br>Friend puts on some sunglasses. <br>Penelope and Friend establish a rapport, donning and removing their respective face coverings, while Gerda and Red look on in bewilderment. <br>Red asks what Friend is doing here. It beckons, chatters, and skitters toward the well, mentioning "Imaginary friends." The party follows; Penelope eagerly, Red cautiously, and Gerda resignedly.<br><img alt="left hmed" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/friend's-well.jpg"><br>Friend excitedly and frantically shows off its collection of "wands," bones, fur (lots of purple fur), books, and maps.<br>Gerda's eye is caught by a rowan wand, and for a moment, she moves to pick it up, before stopping herself. Noticing, Friend offers the wand to Gerda, which she cautiously accepts.<br>Red asks if Friend is there alone, or if there are others. In response, Friend introduces the various dummies and dressing dolls as its friends. Bartholomew, Steve, Teapot, and Daisy are seated around a table set with what may once have been considered food.<br>Gerda again hears the chattering of many overlapping voices. Realizing her concern, Friend refers to the noises she must be hearing as "Stinkies," and sprinkles some purple pelts before them, repeating "Stinkies." The smell gives the distinctive stench of the <a data-href="Abyss" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Abyss" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Abyss</a>. Friend points in the direction of the manor, indicating that many of the Stinkies were there. <br>Elwing billows his cloak about him, before packing it away again.<br>Penelope asked Friend whether they ought to be concerned about the Stinkies. Friend offers to show Penelope, and she agrees. Red follows, as does Gerda, despite her obvious skepticism as to the wisdom of this course of action.<br>The party climbs up the well into the dark of the night. They enter the manor, which is in disarray.<br>Friend interprets the chattering voices as they approach: <br>Stinkies
All hail the rotten Lord of the three threes! All hail the keeper of the ever lost!! Return to us, oh Shadow that Was!! Return!!!!!
<br>Gerda clearly has trepidations about continuing, but Penelope and Red want to at least investigate, to know whether these demonic creatures were trying to summon something worse, and whether they were a threat.<br><img alt="right hmed" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gibberling_5e.jpg"><br>When Gerda indicates that there are only just a few creatures, Penelope sees this as a reason to proceed, feeling that interrupting the summoning which she's sure must be taking place would make them heroes. They open the door, to see another hallway. <br>Feeling a familiar coldness emanating from a room opposite the hallway, Red goes to investigate, finding <a data-href="cavern roses" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/cavern roses" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">cavern roses</a>, which he's seen in his world before. He is concerned by their presence, but doesn't have long to examine them before he's alerted to the sound of Friend and Penelope entering the room down the hall with the Stinkies.<br>Behind the door, which opens with no resistance, are three of the creatures. Penelope charges in, followed by Friend. Hearing the commotion, Gerda joined the fighting, throwing her filet knife as though it were a dart, hitting a Stinky. Red was close behind. Successfully charming one of the creatures, Red asks it, "Why are you here?" It responds in <a data-href="Abyssal" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Abyssal" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Abyssal</a>, which Friend interprets: <br>Stinky
To make mischief and to eat (to eat, to eat). <br>
You're powerful. We could use that. Give me some of your hair.
<br>In response, he takes a swipe at the demon, which dodges, cackling, before biting the elf. Penelope lunges forward, swinging an axe, before Friend stabs the creature, ending it. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
<a data-href="Gerda 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/gerda-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda 1</a>
<a data-href="Penelope 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/penelope-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope 1</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/archive-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session logs/1/Archive 1.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 21:22:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/twin-trees.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/twin-trees.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gerda 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Flamecrest 1, 32<br>Oh my heart, I cannot seem to organize my thoughts as tidily as when I could share them with you. Perhaps writing them down will help to clarify things.<br>I've been dreaming of the two trees again. The moment I close my eyes I see them standing in that cursed plain and I feel that wretched tug to follow the road. I hoped this would be the time that I could ignore it and stay safe alone at home but if anything it has only grown in intensity. I had to leave and I am sorry. I asked the ivy to please not grow over your marker since I won't be able to prune it.<br>On the way a strange urchin named <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a> attached herself to my side. She is small and noisy with many strange devices attached to her. She talks as though speech will be banned in the next moment, but her chattering feels oddly comforting and since we were traveling the same direction it didn't seem necessary to avoid her company. Eventually we met a strange fae with a cloak of leaves and a reserved demeanor. The name they gave was <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Elwing" data-href="Elwing" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Red</a> and given the stories I've heard, perhaps I too should have been more careful...<br>The sky grew dark and rain seemed likely. I decided to head for a ruined set of buildings to make some sort of shelter. To my great surprise and fear, they were already inhabited by a fearsome creature with hard plates like a bug and fierce pincers. Penelope and Red seemed to be able to communicate with it almost immediately and followed it down a well. I would have much preferred to stay up top but I find myself more and more concerned with the safety of these children.<br>Inside the well, it became obvious the creature is lonely. <a data-href="Friend" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Friend</a>, as it appears to call itself, (inside the well I began to hear a voice in my head that I believe to the creature, a minor horror I am choosing not to think about at the moment) has been living here and has killed some number of demonic furry creatures. Penelope grew excited at this and she, Red and Friend all left the well to hunt for more in the large house. Inside the house we began to explore and identified a space where more seemed to lurk. However Red chose to take a detour and though conflicted, I followed Red to a separate room but before anything happened, I heard a great crashing noise. Penelope and Friend must have rushed into danger! I returned to the hallway to see that they had entered the room with the demons. I only had time to throw my filet knife before the fight ended so perhaps my fear was unnecessary. Regardless, if I am going to remain with this trio of peculiar creatures I am going to have to get used to danger it seems.<br>May we meet again, my heart<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
<a data-href="Archive 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/archive-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archive 1</a>
<a data-href="Penelope 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/penelope-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope 1</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/gerda-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session logs/1/Gerda 1.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 22:25:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Penelope 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a>’s Super Heroic Adventure Log<br>
Entry 1<br>
Flamecrest 1, 32 (3rd Age) (Apparently the people of this plane actually care about measuring time. That’s going to take some getting used to…)<br>I found out that my adventuring supplies had this notebook in it, so I’m keeping a log of my adventure in the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Rakāuvi" data-href="Rakāuvi" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/rakāuvi.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Prime Material</a>. You need some record of your heroics to be a real hero, right? So I figured I'd make that record for myself! After a really enthusiastic sendoff, I left the village where I landed. Apparently the locals call this place <a data-href="Yewdon" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Yewdon" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Yewdon</a>, and there’s occasional miasma events??? That seems dangerous, I should look into upgrading my mask with some sort of filters. <a data-href="Steel Jack" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Steel Jack" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Steel Jack</a> had something like that for when the reactor of <a data-href="Jackknife" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Jackknife" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Jackknife</a> starting spitting out fumes. It’s a shame I never got to see it for myself, that could have been helpful…<br>Right, I’m off track, I started off to follow those dreams I had that brought me here. Along the way, I ran into an old Firbolg, who apparently had the same dreams as me! Well, I didn’t find that out until later, but maybe the order of things doesn’t have to be exact. The point is, her name is <a data-href="Gerda" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda</a> and we started walking together, except she moves a lot faster than me with my short legs. We got to the plain from my dreams, the one with the trees, and we ran into some sort of Fae person there too. He showed up in a flurry of autumn leaves, though he wouldn’t tell us his name, so I’m just calling him <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Elwing" data-href="Elwing" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Red</a> until he wants to share (don’t worry, I asked and he’s fine with it).<br>Gerda said that there was something called “rain” coming, which is apparently when the sky starts to just drop water on you. (There’s so many weird things about this plane.) Luckily there was a ruined village nearby, so we stopped there for shelter. (Side note: this would be an AMAZING place to live, there’s so much stuff to fix!) Living in one of the barns was an insect, but like a big one! And it could talk (kinda)! It called itself “<a data-href="Friend" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Friend</a>” so that’s what I’m calling it. Friend seems to have been living here for a bit down a well, and it definitely seemed happy to have some real company. (Side note: we definitely need to clean up for it, its well is messier than my workshop back on <a data-href="Cados" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Cados" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Cados</a>.)<br>Friend showed us around its well and told us about “Stinkies” (that name is definitely accurate) that were in the mansion next to the well, so I asked to see them. Friend took us up to the mansion and after some brief investigative work, we sprung into action and took them out. Oh, right! They were chanting about the Rotten Lord of the Three Threes, which sounds like some bad demon stuff… But we dealt with them, so we’re basically already heroes! Elwing and Gerda even came running over to help, so I think they care more than they’re letting on. Those demons are no match for the power of The Dream Team! (Get it? Because we all had a dream… well actually Friend doesn’t sleep… I guess we all had a vision of this place. Close enough.)<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
<a data-href="Archive 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/archive-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archive 1</a>
<a data-href="Gerda 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/gerda-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda 1</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/1/penelope-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session logs/1/Penelope 1.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 22:25:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Archive 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Session 2
September 8th, 2024 (CE)<br>
Flamecrest 1, 32 (3rd Age)
<br><br>Now that the Stinkies no longer draw breath, the party gets a better look at their surroundings. The room they're in is full of broken musical instruments. <a data-href="Gerda" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda</a> retrieves her thrown filet knife from one of the creatures, and lights up the room to get a better look around. Several beautiful music boxes at the far end of the room become illuminated.<br>
<img alt="hsmall right" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/music-boxes.png"><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a> immediately goes to the trinkets, testing them out. Two are functional, but one of the boxes has a little figurine elf which looks to have once been able to dance, but no longer. Penelope puts the inoperative music box in her bag to fix later. Gerda reprimands Penelope for taking someone else's property, but the gnome holds her ground, citing adventurers' rights- there are no longer any living souls around with a better claim to the loot than the party.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Elwing" data-href="Elwing" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Red</a> examines one of the music boxes, noting its fairy with butterfly wings, indicative of the <a data-href="Summer" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Summer" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Summer</a> court. He activates the device, listening to its tune. As it ends, the tiny fairy springs up with a slight crackle of static electricity. Red considers how strange it is to find so many items from <a data-href="the Feywild" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/the-feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Feywild</a> in this <a data-href="Yewdon" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Yewdon" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Yewdon</a> manor, adding the music box to his bag.<br><br>Gerda examines the remaining music box, which has an elemental figure moving through a slow, controlled series of moves. Like her companions, Gerda stows the box in her bag. Aware of this seeming disparity to her earlier words to Penelope, Gerda comments that she wouldn't want to break up the set.<br><br>Friend picks at the harp, before riffling through some musical scrolls at the piano. They discard the scrolls with any musical notation, keeping the ones that were blank.<br>Now that combat has ended, Red wants to return to the room with the <a data-href="cavern roses" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/cavern roses" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">cavern roses</a>. The others need no convincing to follow. Gerda and Red examine them together. The faint fragrance is reminiscent of honeysuckle; the purple and blue flowers- which have already bloomed once- are ready to bloom again.<br>
These cavern roses are on the outer bounds of the flower patch, and have been growing unchecked for at least a year or two. Gerda suggests going through the nearby door, behind which there are likely more flowers. As she pushes it open, the air becomes noticeably colder.<br>
<br><br><img alt="hmed left" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/cold-iron-cavern-rose.png"><br>In the next room is a banquet table that looks to be set up for a feast. Fine dishes and plush chairs surround the table, covered by many, many more cavern roses, and some big ones. The floor above the largest flower has collapsed downward, and Friend can see a faint blue pulsing light fading in and out through the hole to the room above.<br>Friend
Stars...
<br>Red picks up a sample of one of the smaller flowers, breaking about half of the roots, but probably not enough to kill it. Gerda cuts a bit of the plant off, briefly staining her knife, before wiping it away.<br>The tips of the spiked vines sway slightly, despite there being no breeze. Friend wants to get to the "stars" by way of the plants, but Penelope suggests taking the stairs to get to the room above.<br>Upstairs, the party enters a greenhouse-like scene. The carpet is soaked and stained with rotting leaves. A stone enclosure surrounds a garden of three enormous trees and bunches of flowers. The leftmost tree is an oak, with bark that seems to glow with gold and amber. The center tree is blue, with metallic, glowing globes growing from its branches. On the right is a maple tree, which Red recognizes from his own <a data-href="Autumn" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Autumn" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Autumn</a> court.<br>
<img alt="trees in manor.JPG" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/trees-in-manor.jpg"><br>
These three fey trees are young, perhaps 5 or 6 years old. Although they once had been planted and tended to, they seem to have been abandoned, not having been pruned or cared for recently.  <br><br><br>Knowing little about these trees, Gerda goes to examine a desk, which holds an hourglass and some alchemical equipment. Most of the bottles are partially destroyed, their contents long since evaporated, but Gerda she finds two unbroken bottles- one contains a potion of comprehend languages, and the other is a potion of climbing.<br><br>Penelope moves on, opening the door that most directly leads to Friend's "star." The room is dusty, with desks full of ink bottles, ink stones, and packages wrapped in oil cloth. An open scroll can be seen, with writing in an elvish script. Some letters are folded into little paper tressym- cats with wings.<br><br><br><br><img alt="hm-sm right" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/kazaran-symbol.jpg"><br>On the other side of the room is an altar that was once been arranged with flowers, ferns, and what might be memorial tablets. A symbol is visible, a spiral that blooms into leaves, denoting <a data-href="Kaza'ran" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Kaza'ran" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Kaza'ran</a>. Gerda lights the candles, murmuring an apology to the deity of life for the altar's lack of care.<br><br>Red looks through the shelves and papers. The family seems to have been named Greysky. The documents are invitations, some half-written, others already folded into tressym. The letters are addressed to other Greysky families, inviting them to visit and see their success. Red surveys the room, so clearly set to entertain, and wonders aloud what happened and whether the visitors ever came.<br><br>Friend adds some of the ink stones to its collection. The bundled packets contain pale blue-grey leaves, which gave off a fine fragrance. Seeing no other immediate uses for the leaves, Friend proceeds to munch on the contents of one package. Gerda comments that it would be nice to have tea some evening. Friend obligingly hands the remaining packets over to the firbolg, who seems to know what to do with them, and has somewhat more refined intentions.<br><br>Penelope starts examining the north wall, reasoning that the area behind some ivy might be soft enough to punch through, and far more direct than taking the hallway which connected the rooms. She catapults the fern pot against the wall, successfully making a hole large enough to crawl through.<br><br><img alt="hmed left" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/silver-mithral-lead-box.png"><br>In the room beyond, a glowing, silvery box sits atop some splintered planks and boards, next to a hole in the floor. The box is a small, square chest, tipped over on its side. The outside shines with hints of mithral, while the inside is lined with lead (which Penelope explains has the ability to block detection magic). Its lid, which has a star on it, is swung open in the direction of the hole. Any contents the box may have once contained have long since fallen down to the floor below. Penelope wonders whether the cavern rose seeds were what it was meant to hold.<br>
<br>Friend looks through a stack of books. It leafs through one title in particular, Shameful Swordplay: How to Fake Being a Martial Archetype with any Style of Magic by Telvrin Melkar. The volume details the use of illusion and trickery to boost combat abilities, mimicking physical weapons with magic, and most importantly: how to win and NOT get caught when using the techniques described within. The book has been banned in the Irieaboreal Empire, to the east of Yewdon.<br>The next room, mostly overgrown with plants, is a huge bedroom, where the party decides to take a long rest.<br><br>Friend takes first watch.<br><br>Gerda and Penelope each dream of the barren plain and the twin trees. <br><br>Red trances. <br>He sees a necklace with a little sprig of red pine needles, something Delight always has with her. For the first time, instead of seeing a vision of the plain, he sees Delight's hand, fiddling with the necklace. She is in a spiral staircase going down, down, down. At first the footsteps are quick and energetic, but as the dream continues, Delight seems to be getting fatigued, as each step becomes more difficult.<br>
Just before waking, Red sees a door. He cannot see what's inside, but a pale yellow-green light is shining under the door. For an instant, Red forgets Delight, feeling only the desire to get to the door and pass through it. <br>He awakens as Friend rouses him for his turn to take watch. It then takes up a spot on the floor, where it spends the remainder of the night, motionless.  <br><br><br>Recite
Flamecrest 2, 32 (3rd Age)
<br>Day comes again. Light pours in through the damaged ceiling. <br>Penelope, bright eyed from not having taken a watch, approaches the still motionless Friend, taking a few measurements and assessing the creature's general head shape. She makes some adjustments to the top hat she'd snagged from the closet the day before, modifying it to fit her towering Friend.<br>
Upon completion, Friend chitters excitedly, striking poses and attempting to look regal in the hat they have long coveted.<br>
The gnome isn't finished giving gifts, though. She approaches Gerda, offering her a set of dark vision goggles. They are similar to the ones she herself wears, but they have clearly been designed to fit the firbolg's more homey, utilitarian style, rather than Penelope's flair for the flamboyant. <br>
Throughout all this, the artificer is noticeably less encumbered by the many backpacks and bags she'd previously been carrying. In explanation, she shows off her new fanny pack of holding, and offers to carry things for her companions as well.<br><br>The party discusses their next course of action. Penelope wants to continue looking around before departing toward the twin trees. It wouldn't be very heroic to leave these problematic roses to grow and spread.<br><br><br>Using his smithing tools, Red examines the mithral box they'd found the previous day. Constellations decorate the exterior, with each star made up of a <a data-href="draconic" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/draconic" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">draconic</a> character. The exquisite craftsmanship combined with the draconic script indicate that this box was constructed by a metallic dragon, or someone who studied under one.<br>At Penelope's request, Friend tosses the gnome across the hole in the floor of the room. Penelope lands on the far side and opens a door to find a vine-filled hallway. She follows it around, sneaking to the far side of the party, purposefully startling her companions. <br><br>Gerda, having only just been spooked by Penelope, feels a light tickle on her neck. She is startled to find a tawny owl feather to be the source, but looking up to the various holes in the ceiling, can see nothing to indicate its origin. Disconcerted, she pockets the feather.<br><br><br>The firbolg suggests dangling Penelope down through the hole in the floor, to the maw of the enormous flower below, where whatever was in the silver box must have fallen. Although this proposal was made somewhat wryly, the gnome's approval is sincere.<br>Penelope
"I'm ready to be a hero!"
<br>They fashion a climbing harness and fling the free line over a beam that still seems secure. A second line of rope is looped and knotted around Gerda, who will act as an anchor, keeping Penelope from falling too far. Friend is the one lowering the rope. <br>"Don't think of squids," Penelope repeats to herself as she slowly descends. <br><img alt="hmed right" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/grabby-stick.png"><br>Struck with inspiration, Penelope requests that she be pulled up again briefly. She tinkers and fiddles for a few minutes, fashioning a Grabby Claw to extend her reach by 5 feet.<br><br>She gets lowered once more to the floral maw, new device in hand. As she pokes around,  the flower begins to close around the claw, and Penelope narrowly withdraws her tool before the petals surround it completely.<br>She notices that the cool mist they've been seeing in the manor seems to be emitted from the maw.<br>
Red observes that the little tips of the vines start moving a bit more, as though it is beginning to wake. <br>Gerda
"I'm willing to risk Penelope one more time."
<br>For the third time, Penelope is pulleyed down until she can reach around in the plant once more. The claw clinks against something hard and she withdraws her tool with the object in its clasp.<br>Friend pulls Penelope up, and as she rises, so does the cold and mist. <br>Penelope produces the lead-lined box from her pack and drops the prize inside, where it can finally be seen by the party. <br>The item is a metallic, blue-grey pearl the size of a walnut. Friend feels something akin to nausea from the item's proximity, and Red is likewise unsettled. He names the pearl as cold iron, a material that is deadly to fey.<br><br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-logs/2/archive-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session logs/2/Archive 2.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 22:09:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/music-boxes.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/music-boxes.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Cards

<br><br>


<br><br>
Between five and thirty years ago (depending on what plane you're from) there was a massive arcane cataclysm called the <a data-href="Spellplague" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Spellplague" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spellplague</a> that caused all magic to stop functioning. Many of the most advanced mages and healers perished as a wave of blue fire swept the realms. Cities fell from the sky, planes crashed into one another, rifts opened to the <a data-href="Hells" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Hells" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hells</a> and <a data-href="the Abyss" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/the Abyss" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Abyss</a> as fiends of all sorts took advantage of the chaos.<br>
As time passed, magic seemed to slowly return. Magic, which some call the Weave, is an arcane tapestry into which some mortals are able to tap. Whether the magic presents as gifts from the deities, a connection to nature, a bond with an otherworldly entity, or the reward after years of practice and study, it has only begun to express itself in the past two decades as the worlds began to heal from the Spellplague.<br>
Some people are able to reconnect with magic they lost during the years of chaos, others have developed power when they never had any before.

<br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 23:18:29 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/elwing.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/elwing.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rakāuvi]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Prime Material Plane is the "Earth" of this world, called Rakāuvi. There are two planes that mirror different aspects of the Prime Material Plane, <a data-href="The Feywild" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/the-feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Feywild</a> and <a data-href="the Shadowfel" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/the-shadowfel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Shadowfel</a>. These three planes together are often referred to as the "close planes". Major environmental or enormous magical effects will echo from one close plane to the others.<br>The world of Rakāuvi is full of many races, none are considered banned or automatically discriminated against, though some are rarer than others (or rare in certain regions) and may draw attention as a result. <br>On Rakāuvi, there are many small villages (20-100 people) and towns (100-1000), some cities (1000-10,000), with very few enormous city-centers (over 10,000 citizens).<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/rakāuvi.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/Rakāuvi.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:29:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elwing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg">




<br><br><br>Measuring four feet tall, Elwing's young face, old eyes, and terse demeanor are mysterious and somewhat difficult for people to read. He carries a longbow and a staff surrounded by ever-blooming leaves, which change with his intentions and mood. At times, he wears a cloak which likewise billows with leaves. <br>Elwing does not warm easily to others. Indeed, upon first meeting the party, he preferred to go by "Red," an offhand nickname given to him by <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a>, rather than reveal his own name just yet.<br>Although the half-elf's motives are unclear, his relative standoffishness does not indicate apathy towards the other members of the party; despite telling the party that he would take care of them should they follow him, he rapidly came to Penelope's and <a data-href="Friend" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Friend</a>'s aid upon hearing the commotion of combat.<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Elwing.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gerda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png">




<br><br><br>Gerda doesn't need her quarterstaff to stand to her full height of 7 feet, but as a dweller of the forest, she keeps her walking stick with her for utilitarian purposes.<br>The firbolg has blue-grey skin and salt-and-pepper hair in a simple braid down to her low back. Her clothes, while homey and simple, are clearly well cared for, having been mended many times. <br>She carries filet and chef's knifes strapped to her hip, and her various pockets and pouches are filled with mushrooms and herbalism components, which she constantly forages.<br>Gerda is no spring chicken. Her demeanor is stern and imposing, but her uninviting nature warms with familiarity. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Gerda.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Penelope Tillnot]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png">




<br><br><br>Penelope Tillnot is enthusiastically curious, with no apparent boundaries to her interests or inquiries. She eagerly forges friendships (sometimes unilaterally), and does not seem to be put off by much.<br>She wears and carries a collection of mis-matched tools, equipment, and attire, which are densely packed about her 3-foot-6 frame. Her medium length hair, which is wild and stained with various substances, is partially obscured by the welding mask and welding goggles she wears. Her jaunty gait doesn't appear to be slowed by the weight of her thick leather blacksmith apron, nor her very heavy bag of supplies containing every tool imaginable (other than camping gear).<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Penelope Tillnot.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Days of the week]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Each month has 3 weeks and 30 days, with ten days per week<br>
<br>Arbor 
<br>Belter 
<br>Cantor 
<br>Fretless 
<br>Greenwave 
<br>Loresun 
<br>Ternstay 
<br>Windwill 
<br>Veilnor 
<br>Yarnallow
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/days-of-the-week.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Days of the week.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:27:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Month names]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Sproutsurge 
<br>Dewfall 
<br>Bloomwave 
<br><br>
<br>Flamecrest 
<br>Highsun 
<br>Shadeveil 
<br><br>
<br>Mirthwind 
<br>Galesong 
<br>Windfellow 
<br><br>
<br>Breezemist 
<br>Lumis 
<br>Chillglow
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/month-names.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Month names.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:26:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Races & Lifespans of most races]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Aasimar &amp; Tieflings: 150-200 
<br>Beastfolk: 100-200 (includes aarakocra, kenku, owlin, shifters, tabaxi) 
<br>Dragonkind: 80-300 (includes dragonborn, kobolds, lizardfolk, tortle, and yuan ti) 
<br>Dwarves: 300-400 
<br>Elves: 600-700 
<br>Fey races 100-300 (includes changlings, centaurs, fairies, harengone, minotaur, satyr) 
<br>Genasi: 150-300 
<br>Giantkin: 200-500 (includes firbolg and goliath) 
<br>Gnomes: 600-700 
<br>Goblinkind: 50-200 (includes bugbears, goblins, and hobgoblins) 
<br>Half-elves: 150-250 
<br>Half-orcs: 100-200 
<br>Halflings: 100-300 
<br>Orcs: 100-300 
<br>Triton: 150-300
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/races-&amp;-lifespans-of-most-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Races &amp; Lifespans of most races.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 12:45:23 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>