<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Dream Team]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/</link><image><url>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Dream Team</title><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:37:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:37:51 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Rakāuvi]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Prime Material Plane is the "Earth" of this world, called Rakāuvi. There are two planes that mirror different aspects of the Prime Material Plane, <a data-href="The Feywild" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/the-feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Feywild</a> and <a data-href="the Shadowfel" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/the-shadowfel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Shadowfel</a>. These three planes together are often referred to as the "close planes". Major environmental or enormous magical effects will echo from one close plane to the others.<br>The world of Rakāuvi is full of many races, none are considered banned or automatically discriminated against, though some are rarer than others (or rare in certain regions) and may draw attention as a result. <br>On Rakāuvi, there are many small villages (20-100 people) and towns (100-1000), some cities (1000-10,000), with very few enormous city-centers (over 10,000 citizens).<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/locations/rakāuvi.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Locations/Rakāuvi.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:29:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elwing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg">




<br><br><br>Measuring four feet tall, Elwing's young face, old eyes, and terse demeanor are mysterious and somewhat difficult for people to read. He carries a longbow and a staff surrounded by ever-blooming leaves, which change with his intentions and mood. At times, he wears a cloak which likewise billows with leaves. <br>Elwing does not warm easily to others. Indeed, upon first meeting the party, he preferred to go by "Red," an offhand nickname given to him by <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a>, rather than reveal his own name just yet.<br>Although the half-elf's motives are unclear, his relative standoffishness does not indicate apathy towards the other members of the party; despite telling the party that he would take care of them should they follow him, he rapidly came to Penelope's and <a data-href="Friend" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Friend</a>'s aid upon hearing the commotion of combat.<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Elwing.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/elwing.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Friend]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png">




<br><br><br>They're a monstrosity, but don't let that scare you off.<br>
Standing 8 feet tall with 4 arms, Friend is available (and eager) for a hug. Their home is a well, filled with piles of skins, brooms, equipment, and junk that Friend has collected. They also have a table set (with foods in various states of decay) for several dummies and dressing dolls, which Friend introduces as Bartholomew, Steve, Teapot, and Daisy. <br>Friend communicates telepathically to those who are willing, speaking in short, halting phrases. Their enormous insectoid figure may be intimidating, but Friend's enthusiastic waving of three arms in greeting, as well as the wailing music they play, appear to be overzealous efforts to befriend the party, apparently on the advice of Daisy. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/friend.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Friend.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/i.-friend.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gerda]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png">




<br><br><br>Gerda doesn't need her quarterstaff to stand to her full height of 7 feet, but as a dweller of the forest, she keeps her walking stick with her for utilitarian purposes.<br>The firbolg has blue-grey skin and salt-and-pepper hair in a simple braid down to her low back. Her clothes, while homey and simple, are clearly well cared for, having been mended many times. <br>She carries filet and chef's knifes strapped to her hip, and her various pockets and pouches are filled with mushrooms and herbalism components, which she constantly forages.<br>Gerda is no spring chicken. Her demeanor is stern and imposing, but her uninviting nature warms with familiarity. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Gerda.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/gerda.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Penelope Tillnot]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Infobox

<img alt="wsmall" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png">




<br><br><br>Penelope Tillnot is enthusiastically curious, with no apparent boundaries to her interests or inquiries. She eagerly forges friendships (sometimes unilaterally), and does not seem to be put off by much.<br>She wears and carries a collection of mis-matched tools, equipment, and attire, which are densely packed about her 3-foot-6 frame. Her medium length hair, which is wild and stained with various substances, is partially obscured by the welding mask and welding goggles she wears. Her jaunty gait doesn't appear to be slowed by the weight of her thick leather blacksmith apron, nor her very heavy bag of supplies containing every tool imaginable (other than camping gear).<br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Player Characters/Penelope Tillnot.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:43:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/lib/media/penelope-tillnot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Days of the week]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Each month has 3 weeks and 30 days, with ten days per week<br>
<br>Arbor 
<br>Belter 
<br>Cantor 
<br>Fretless 
<br>Greenwave 
<br>Loresun 
<br>Ternstay 
<br>Windwill 
<br>Veilnor 
<br>Yarnallow
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/days-of-the-week.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Days of the week.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:27:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Month names]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
<br>Sproutsurge 
<br>Dewfall 
<br>Bloomwave 
<br><br>
<br>Flamecrest 
<br>Highsun 
<br>Shadeveil 
<br><br>
<br>Mirthwind 
<br>Galesong 
<br>Windfellow 
<br><br>
<br>Breezemist 
<br>Lumis 
<br>Chillglow
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/month-names.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Month names.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 02:26:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Races & Lifespans of most races]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>Aasimar &amp; Tieflings: 150-200 
<br>Beastfolk: 100-200 (includes aarakocra, kenku, owlin, shifters, tabaxi) 
<br>Dragonkind: 80-300 (includes dragonborn, kobolds, lizardfolk, tortle, and yuan ti) 
<br>Dwarves: 300-400 
<br>Elves: 600-700 
<br>Fey races 100-300 (includes changlings, centaurs, fairies, harengone, minotaur, satyr) 
<br>Genasi: 150-300 
<br>Giantkin: 200-500 (includes firbolg and goliath) 
<br>Gnomes: 600-700 
<br>Goblinkind: 50-200 (includes bugbears, goblins, and hobgoblins) 
<br>Half-elves: 150-250 
<br>Half-orcs: 100-200 
<br>Halflings: 100-300 
<br>Orcs: 100-300 
<br>Triton: 150-300
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/races-&amp;-lifespans-of-most-races.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and Phrases/Races &amp; Lifespans of most races.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 12:45:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Index]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Between five and thirty years ago (depending on what plane you're from) there was a massive arcane cataclysm called the <a data-href="Spellplague" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Spellplague" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spellplague</a> that caused all magic to stop functioning. Many of the most advanced mages and healers perished as a wave of blue fire swept the realms. Cities fell from the sky, planes crashed into one another, rifts opened to the <a data-href="Hells" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Hells" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hells</a> and <a data-href="the Abyss" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/the Abyss" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Abyss</a> as fiends of all sorts took advantage of the chaos. 
As time passed, magic seemed to slowly return. Magic, which some call the Weave, is an arcane tapestry into which some mortals are able to tap. Whether the magic presents as gifts from the deities, a connection to nature, a bond with an otherworldly entity, or the reward after years of practice and study, it has only begun to express itself in the past two decades as the worlds began to heal from the Spellplague. 
Some people are able to reconnect with magic they lost during the years of chaos, others have developed power when they never had any before.
<br>Info

<br><br>Cards

<br><br>Player Characters

<br><br>
<br><a data-href="Session 1" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Session 1</a>
<br><br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
<br><br>]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 21:37:37 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/elwing.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/elwing.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Session 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Session 1
September 1st, 2024 (CE)<br>
Flamecrest 1, 32 (3rd Age)
<br>We begin in <a data-href="Yewdon" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Yewdon" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Yewdon</a>, where the winters are mild, and the summers are wet and damp.<br>
Going in the same direction on converging paths, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Penelope Tillnot" data-href="Penelope Tillnot" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/penelope-tillnot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Penelope</a> and <a data-href="Gerda" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/gerda.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Gerda</a> meet. They discuss height differences and thought- versus leg-powered locomotion with a juxtaposition of skepticism and enthusiasm. Penelope mentioned <a data-href="Steel Jack" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Steel Jack" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Steel Jack</a>, a mentor she'd had. <br>They see a wide open plain ahead of them with two trees among the emptiness where a forest used to be.<br><img alt="twin trees.PNG" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/twin-trees.png"><br>They notice a vortex of leaves ahead around <a data-href="Elwing" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/player-characters/elwing.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Elwing</a>. Penelope greets him, and he gives curt replies. Penelope reveals that she's here because of a dream. Elwing is too, sort of. Gerda indicates that she, too, has had a dream, but recoils at Penelope's enthusiasm. Given what they share in common, Penelope comments on the group being a "Dream Team."<br>The wind picks up, and some dark clouds start rolling in, indicating rain within the hour. They see a collection of abandoned, ruined homes off ahead, on the way toward the twin trees. Gerda starts toward the collection of shelters, signaling to the others that they could join. <br>Gerda
"Do you want to get wet?"
<br>Penelope gives Elwing the nickname "Red," when he declines to give his name.<br>
Rain begins, which Penelope has never seen before, to Gerda's astonishment.<br>
As they continue, Gerda gathers kindling. Elwing notices that the closer they get to the houses, the cooler the air has gotten.<br>There are rifts in the ground, so dark and deep that the bottom can't be seen. A strange noise emits from the manor, separate from the creaky gate swinging in the wind. It sounds like it could have been chattering voices, turning into a wailing scream, which fades into the chattering, followed by a wailing scream again.<br>Red and Penelope are concerned, but Gerda is unbothered. When she sees how earnestly concerned Penelope is about the sound, however, she pauses. As they make their way around the manor and hear the wail again.<br>Elwing tells the others that he's going to find the source of the sound, but that he won't be taking care of them if they follow.<br>Inside, there are piles of skin, dead bodies in various states of decomposition, brooms, junk, equipment. It's messy, but there is intent in the organization.<br>A tall figure in the darkness of the barn emerges, swinging a tube on a string, which makes the wailing noise they had been hearing. The creature's other three arms are waving frantcally.<br>Elwing speaks to the creature in Sylvan, asking who they are. It replies in an insectoid clicking sound, saying telepetathically "Friend, Friend."<br>Friend
"Hello, hello. Do you like music?"
<br>Its three arms continue waving hard, expressing a fervent greeting,  as it swings the screaming device. <br>Gerda draws her chef's knife to the ready. Penelope puts their welding mask down. <br>Friend puts on some sunglasses. <br>Penelope and Friend establish a rapport, donning and removing their respective face coverings, while Gerda and Red look on in bewilderment. <br>Red asks what Friend is doing here. It beckons, chatters, and skitters toward the well, mentioning "Imaginary friends." The party follows; Penelope eagerly, Red cautiously, and Gerda resignedly.<br><img alt="left hmed" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/friend's-well.jpg"><br>Friend excitedly and frantically shows off its collection of "wands," bones, fur (lots of purple fur), books, and maps.<br>Gerda's eye is caught by a rowan wand, and for a moment, she moves to pick it up, before stopping herself. Noticing, Friend offers the wand to Gerda, which she cautiously accepts.<br>Red asks if Friend is there alone, or if there are others. In response, Friend introduces the various dummies and dressing dolls as its friends. Bartholomew, Steve, Teapot, and Daisy are seated around a table set with what may once have been considered food.<br>Gerda again hears the chattering of many overlapping voices. Realizing her concern, Friend refers to the noises she must be hearing as "Stinkies," and sprinkles some purple pelts before them, repeating "Stinkies." The smell gives the distinctive stench of the <a data-href="Abyss" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/Abyss" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Abyss</a>. Friend points in the direction of the manor, indicating that many of the Stinkies were there. <br>Elwing billows his cloak about him, before packing it away again.<br>Penelope asked Friend whether they ought to be concerned about the Stinkies. Friend offers to show Penelope, and she agrees. Red follows, as does Gerda, despite her obvious skepticism as to the wisdom of this course of action.<br>The party climbs up the well into the dark of the night. They enter the manor, which is in disarray.<br>Friend interprets the chattering voices as they approach: <br>Stinkies
All hail the rotten Lord of the three threes! All hail the keeper of the ever lost!! Return to us, oh Shadow that Was!! Return!!!!!
<br>Gerda clearly has trepidations about continuing, but Penelope and Red want to at least investigate, to know whether these demonic creatures were trying to summon something worse, and whether they were a threat.<br><img alt="right hmed" src="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/gibberling_5e.jpg"><br>When Gerda indicates that there are only just a few creatures, Penelope sees this as a reason to proceed, feeling that interrupting the summoning which she's sure must be taking place would make them heroes. They open the door, to see another hallway. <br>Feeling a familiar coldness emanating from a room opposite the hallway, Red goes to investigate, finding <a data-href="cavern roses" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/cavern roses" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">cavern roses</a>, which he's seen in his world before. He is concerned by their presence, but doesn't have long to examine them before he's alerted to the sound of Friend and Penelope entering the room down the hall with the Stinkies.<br>Behind the door, which opens with no resistance, are three of the creatures. Penelope charges in, followed by Friend. Hearing the commotion, Gerda joined the fighting, filet knife in hand. Red was close behind. Successfully charming one of the creatures, Red asks it, "Why are you here?" It responds in Abyssal, which Friend interprets: <br>Stinky
To make mischief and to eat (to eat, to eat). <br>
You're powerful. We could use that. Give me some of your hair.
<br>In response, he takes a swipe at the demon, which dodges, cackling, before biting Elwing. Penelope lunges forward, swinging an axe, before Friend stabs the creature, ending it. <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
]]></description><link>https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/session-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session 1.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:16:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/twin-trees.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fernhouse-campaign.github.io/images/twin-trees.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>